# ARNAUD GUIBBERT

Data Scientist 🔲 💥

arnaud.guibbert@hotmail.com

LinkedIn

arnaud.guibbert.gitlab.io

London

### ABOUT ME

Efficient and autonomous, I am a Data Scientist with over 2+ years of experience in developing deep learning models and building end to end ML/Data Pipelines. Over the past two years, I have contributed to 4+ projects, three of which have been successfully deployed in production at Swisscom, serving over 15k+ employees.

### SKILLS -

Languages: Python(PyTorch, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Hugging Face, FastAPI, NetworkX, Streamlit),

SQL, C++.

Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Git/GitLab, Air-Technologies:

Flow, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS.

### EXPERIENCE

Swisscom, Switzerland

- · Internal consulting in a team that designs and develops innovative ML and Data-related solutions
- · Leading projects through stakeholders management.
- · Developed and deployed in production a multimodal deep learning model to route IT tickets to the correct department and predict failure risks. Reduced ticket routing time by a factor of 60 and decreased the failure rate. Currently processing over 10,000 tickets weekly.
- Developed a deep learning time series forecasting model to predict daily fluctuations in banking payments volume. Improved forecast accuracy by 60% on average.
- Developed and deployed an intelligent AI assistant with a RAG bot backend to assist operators in resolving banking incidents. Reduced average incident resolution time by a factor of 3.

### 09/2022 - 05/2023 Research Data Scientist

Swisscom, Switzerland

- Internal research consulting team that performs ML research
- · Led a research project to compress large knowlegde graphs using geometric deep-learning. Compressing large knowledge graphs with a factor of 300.

### 

Procsim. Switzerland

- · External consulting in a team that designs metaheuristic algorithms and simulation models.
- · Developed meta-heuristics algorithms to optimize operating room schedules in hospital settings.
- · Developed and deployed simulation models and optimization algorithms to streamline a tyre and a food supply chains. Increased the production rate by a factor of 4.

# 02/2020 - 06/2022 Teaching assistant at EPFL & CentraleSupélec

EPFL & CentraleSupélec

- Teaching assistant in applied & advanced machine learning classes (around 100 students) at EPFL. Aiding students in understanding ML fundamental concepts and supervising projects.
- Teaching assistant in quantum and statistical physics class at CentraleSupélec. Supervision of around 30 students. Teaching basics of quantum physics and preparing short exams for the students.

### **EDUCATION**

### 09/2020 - 04/2023 Data Science - Master's degree at EPFL

Lausanne, Switzerland

Highest GPA (5.78/6) of the Microengineering/Data Science department. Key classes: Stochastic Processes, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Model Predictive Control, Computer Vision, Applied Data Analysis, Graph Theory.

09/2018 - 04/2023

Bachelor's & Master's degree of Science at CentraleSupélec / Paris-Saclay University Paris, France CentraleSupélec/EPFL Double degree, GPA: 4.21/4.33. Key classes: Statistics - Advanced Probability -Quantum and statistical physics - Fluid mechanics - Automation - Electronic systems - Electromagnetism -

09/2016 - 08/2020

# Preparatory class for the 'grandes écoles' at Lycée du Parc

Lvon. France

Intensive training in Mathematics, Physics, Automation & Mechanical engineering.

PROJECTS -

02/2022 - 07/2022

### Neural Architecture Search in complex field for audio recognition

EPFL. ML Research

Developed advanced NAS methods with pairwise operations in the complex field to enhance audio recognition performances. Laboratory for Information and Inference Systems - Volkan Cevher

02/2021 - 06/2021

## **Automatic design of Finite State Machines**

**EPFL**, Optimization Research

Compare different optimization algorithms to generate a Finite State Machine. Solving computationally expensive black box MINLP with surrogate models. Distributed Intelligent Systems and Algorithms -Alcherio Martinoli